<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
  
  <channel>
    
    
    
    
    <title>FunLearn Talks</title>
    
    
    
    
    <description>A fun way to learn interesting topics.</description>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    
    
    
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    
    
    <itunes:image href="https://archive.org/download/show-art/Show_Art.png"/>
    
    
    
    
    <image>
      
      
      
      
      <url>https://archive.org/download/fun-learn/fun-learn.png</url>
      
      
      
      
      <title>FunLearn Talks</title>
      
      
      
      
      <link>https://venom21adi.github.io/pheonix_podcast/index.xml</link>
      
      
    
    
    </image>
    
    
    
    
    <itunes:category text="History"/>
    
    
    
    <itunes:author>Aditya</itunes:author>
    <itunes:owner>
      
      
      
      
      <itunes:name>Aditya</itunes:name>
      
      
      
      
      <itunes:email>pheonixlearn@gmail.com</itunes:email>
      
      
    
    
    </itunes:owner>
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      
      
      
      
      <itunes:image href="https://dn721505.ca.archive.org/0/items/Episode_1-1755491861/Episode_1.png"/>
      
      
      
      
      <title>&quot;Episode 01: Echoes of Innovation: Birmingham's Industrial Boom and the Birth of Cadbury&quot;</title>
      
      
      
      
      <enclosure url="https://ia601003.us.archive.org/25/items/Episode_01-1755491902/Episode_01.mp3" length="248773076" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      
      
      
      
      <description>Dive into the heart of the Industrial Revolution with our latest episode, where we transport you to mid-Victorian Birmingham—a hub of relentless growth and innovation. Picture walking through the smoke-engulfed streets of this bustling metropolis, where towering chimneys dominate the skyline, and the clattering sounds of machinery echo in the air. This episode explores how Birmingham, once a modest market town, exploded into a sprawling industrial giant, home to over 200,000 people by 1850. Discover the products that were forged here, from intricate jewelry to robust machinery, and experience the dual nature of progress marked by both technological advancement and challenging living conditions. Amidst the industrial chaos, uncover the story of a remarkable venture on Bridge Street—the birthplace of the Cadbury cocoa works. Learn how the Cadbury brothers turned their family's faltering business into a beloved global brand, all starting in a backstreet factory infused with the rich aroma of cocoa. Join us as we delve into these fascinating tales of transformation and triumph. Don’t miss this episode! Tune in to feel the pulse of industrial-age Birmingham and savor the sweet success of Cadbury’s revolutionary journey.</description>
      
      
      
      
      <guid>b8c3b02b-3117-5c96-a419-2f0b60a3fb4e</guid>
      
      
      
      
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      
      
    
    
    </item>
    
    
  
    
    <item>
      
      
      <itunes:image href="https://ia800905.us.archive.org/25/items/Episode_2-1755491985/Episode_2.png"/>
      
      
      <title>&quot;Episode 02: From Rags to Riches: Richard Tapper's Journey Through 1780s England&quot;</title>
      
      
      <enclosure url="https://dn720700.ca.archive.org/0/items/Episode_02-1755492027/Episode_02.mp3" length="259336628" type="audio/wav"/>
      
      
      <description>Join us on a captivating journey through the life of Richard Tapper, an ambitious draper whose resilience and innovation navigated the highs and lows of the 18th century. In this episode, we delve into Richard's early days as an apprentice in Kent during the American War of Independence, through the downturn that followed the war's end, to his ultimate rise in the bustling markets of London and Birmingham. Discover how Richard’s determination and strategic moves not only propelled him into mingling with the elite but also led him to establish a thriving business amidst the backdrop of the French Revolution and changing European fashions. Witness the evolution of an entrepreneur who transformed challenges into stepping stones, influencing fashion trends and business norms along the way! We'll explore key lessons from Richard's journey that are still relevant to today’s entrepreneurs and enthusiasts of history and fashion. Get ready to be inspired by a tale of perseverance, vision, and success. Don’t miss this episode of historical escapades and entrepreneurial spirit—tune in now!</description>
      
      
      <guid>d8994fd0-8f78-5b68-8e5a-8ba8a7039a67</guid>
      
      
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      
    
    </item>
    
  
    <item>
      <itunes:image href="https://dn721606.ca.archive.org/0/items/Episode_3-1755449086/Episode_3.png"/>
      <title>&quot;Episode 03: From Cocoa to Queens: The Cadbury Family's Sweet Impact on History&quot;</title>
      <enclosure url="https://ia801004.us.archive.org/14/items/Episode_03-1755449122/Episode_03.mp3" length="260655380" type="audio/wav"/>
      <description>In this captivating episode of our podcast, journey back to the mid-19th century to discover the remarkable story of the Cadbury family—a name synonymous with chocolate, but with a tale that transcends mere confectionery. Dive into the lively narrative of how this iconic household blended entrepreneurship with cultural revolution during an era of extraordinary transformation. We’ll explore the bustling cocoa trade under the innovative leadership of John Cadbury, the challenges and triumphs faced by his descendants, and the visionary creation of a model village that epitomized their commitment to worker welfare. Through steam engines, railway expansions, and youthful escapades like Richard Cadbury’s dawn ice-skating sessions, we unfold how personal passions and societal shifts intertwined to mold a legacy that continues to enchant us today. Unravel how the Cadburys not only navigated but shaped the world’s shifting tides—from industrial progress to royal endorsements. This episode isn't just about chocolate; it’s about the spirit and dreams that flavored the era. Craving a blend of history, inspiration, and allure? Don’t miss this episode! Tune in now to steep yourself in the rich, transforming aromas of the past with ‘The Cadbury Chronicles’.</description>
      <guid>4f5e0839-04e1-59ff-959f-eba5c0a0c095</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 05:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
  
  


</rss>



















